Tatiana Bertazoli

(713) 858-6951

tatianabertazoli@gmail.com https://github.com/TBertazoli

SKILLS

HTML/ CSS / JavaScript / Git / Node.js/ REST API's/ Express.js / PWA/ MySQL / MongoDB/ React

Detailed oriented professional and challenge seeker looking to leverage my analytical skills upon my 16 year of experience as a Chemist by transitioning into the IT industry as a QA Software Engineer.

EXPERIENCE

Rice University, Houston - Texas — *Student*

AUGUST 2022 - JANUARY 2023

- Developed over 30 projects through my coding bootcamp program using different technologies.
- Experience with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Node.js, REST API's, Express.js, MySQL, MongoDB, React and GraphQL.

Westlake Epoxy, Stafford - Texas — R&D Specialist

JANUARY 2019 - PRESENT

• Research and Development of Epoxy resins for Composites application.

Siltech Corporation, Toronto - Canada — *QC Manager*

JUNE 2011 - AUGUST 2018

- Analyzed Chemical products and issued certificate of Analysis
- Reviewed and develop documentation and Standard operating procedures
- Responsible for Chempax software implementation.

Dow Chemical, Jundiai - Brazil — TS&D Chemist

NOVEMBER 2009 - OCTOBER 2010

• Technical service and development of Polyurethane foams.

EDUCATION

Rice University, Houston - Texas — *Full stack web developer*

AUGUST 2022 - IANUARY 2023

Pontifícia Universidade Católica de Campinas, Campinas - Brazil — B.S. Chemistry

JANUARY 2006 - DEZEMBER 2009

PROJECTS

Budget-App

This project is a budget app and was developed as a group assignment. The user has to be logged in to access the features. The user can add expenses, income and set a budget for each category. A progress bar indicates how much of the income was used in the expenses. It also features a calendar that shows the expense for the selected day. The technologies used for this application were: MongoDB, React, React Routes, Express.js, Node.js and GraphQL.

Link: https://oinc.herokuapp.com/

Lab-Notebook

This project is a virtual lab notebook and was developed as a group assignment. The user has to be logged in to access the features of this web application. The user can create, delete and edit projects and experiments as well as add attachments to the experiment and comments. This project was developed using REST API's, Express.js, Node,js, MySQL and handlebars.

Link: https://lab-notes.herokuapp.com/

Text Editor PWA

This project is a text editor web application that works as a progressive web application. When you use the application for the first time you will see a button to install it. If you choose to proceed with installation a shortcut icon should appear on your desktop or your mobile screen. The user can add or delete text and all the information will be stored in an IndexedDP database. The Technologies used for this application were: PWA, HTML, CSS, JavaSCript and Node.js

Link: https://text-editor-pwabertazoli.herokuapp.com/

Weather Dashboard

This project is a weather dashboard that will give you the current forecast and 5 -day forecast for a specific city based on user input. Based on the requirements, the start page is a clean page written in HTML and CSS in the front end and JavaScript in the back end. The user will search for a city and the website will fetch the location and the results will fetch the weather conditions and populate the current forecast for that city. I used local storage to store the 5 most recent searched locations. The technologies used for this application were: HTML, CSS, JavaSCript and API's

Link: https://tbertazoli.github.io/Weather Dashboard/